Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Ives, Hilda Libby
    - All in One Day: Experiences & Insights. Portland, Maine: The Bond Wheelwright Co., 1955. (Box 33)
  - Jensen, Robin Margaret
    - Interpreting Christian Art: a conference on the iconography, historical context and hermeneutical implications of Christian art: October 26–28, 2000. Baylor, Pruit Memorial Symposium: Waco, Texas, 2000. (Box 59)
    - Tuohy Lecture Series 2000: The Substance of Things Seen: Art, Faith, and the Christian Community by Robin Margaret Jensen. The Walter & Mary Tuohy Chair of Interreligious Studies at John Carroll University: Cleveland, Ohio, 2000. (Box 59)
    - Understanding Early Christian Art (London: Routledge, 2000). (Box 59)
    - [Unpublished email re: Jensen's selection as 2001–2002 Henry Luce II Fellow.] 2001 (Box 59)
    - [Unpublished letter re: offer of a Lilly endowment for Jensen.] 2001 (Box 59)
    - "The Sacrifice of Isaac in Early Christian Iconography: Context and Meaning." [no publication information.], no date (Box 59)
    - Bibliography of Robin Margaret Jensen, no date (Box 59)
  - Jeyaraj, Daniel
    - "Missionary Attempts of Tamil Protestant Christians in East and West during the 19th Century." In Transcontinental Links in the History of Non-Western Christianity. Ed. Klaus Koschorke. Wiesbaden: Harrasowitz Verlag, 2002: 131–144. (Box 60)
    - Geneaology of the South Indian Deities: An English translation of Bartholomaus Ziegenbalg's original German manuscript with a textual analysis and Glossary. New York: Routledge Curzon, 2003 (Box 60)
    - "Hallesche Berichte: Quelle zur Sudindienkunde." In Missionsberichte aus Indien Im 18. Jahrhundert. Ed. Michael Bergunder. Verlag der Franckeschen Stiftungen Zu Halle, 2004: 94–110. (Box 60)
    - "Kolonialisme og mission I Tranquebar forholdet til 'hinduerne'." In Det begyndte I Kobenhavn…Knudepunkter I 300 ars indisk relationer I mission. Eds. K. E. Bugge, H.R. Iversen, Niels Kastfelt, Liselotte Malmgart, Harald Nielsen, Anders Norgaard, George Oommen. Syddansk Universitetsforlag, 2005: 86-103 (Box 60)
    - A German Exploration of Indian Society: Ziegenbalg's "Malabarian Heathenism". The Mylapore Institute for Indigenous Studies, Chennai and the Indian Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge, New Delhi, 2006. (Box 60)
    - Bartholomaus Ziegenbalg: the Father of Modern Protestant Mission: An Indian Assessment. New Delhi: Indian Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge and Chennai: Gurukul Lutheran Theological College and Research Institute, 2006. (Box 61)
    - Certificate of Award of Title of Doctor of Divinity (Honoris Causa) from the Academy of Ecumenical Indian Theology and Church Administration, July 7, 2006. (Box 60)
    - "From Outside the Gate into the Gate: an Indian Protestant experiece." In Antioch Agenda, eds. DJ, Robert W. Pazmino, Rodney L. Petersen. New Delhi: Indian Society for the Promotion of Christian Knowledge, 2007: 239–259. (Box 61)
  - Jones, Jeff D.
    - "Retreats—An Answer to Your Youth Group Slump?" Baptist Leader 37/2 (May 1975): 57–60. (Box 33)
    - Organizing a Youth Ministry to Fit Your Needs. Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 1983. (Box 33)
    - Youth Ministry: Making and Sharing Disciples. Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 1986. (Box 33)
    - Facing Decline, Finding Hope: New Possibilities for Faithful Churches. Lanham, Maryland: Rowman & Littlefield, 2015. (Box 33)
  - Jones, Kirk Byron
    - "A Tribute to Samuel D. Proctor: Into the Long Future." Pulpit 1/1 (Winter 1997–98): 14–15. (Box 62)
    - "Editorial Introduction: Joy and Awe." Pulpit 1/1 (Winter 1997–98): 5–7. (Box 62)
    - "Talking About Preaching: An Interview with Henry H. Mitchell." Pulpit 1/1 (Winter 1997–98): 88–93. (Box 62)
    - "The Possessed Exorcist: Ecclesiastical Roles and Agendas in Society." The Pastor Scholar 2/1 (Spring 1997): 14–23. (Box 62)
    - Rest in the Storm: Self-Care Strategies for Clergy and Other Caregivers. Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 2001. (Box 62)
    - Addicted to Hurry: Spiritual Strategies for Slowing Down. Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 2003. (Box 62)
    - The Jazz of Preaching: how to preach with great freedom and joy. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 2004. (Box 62)
    - Morning B.R.E.W.: A Divine Power Drink for Your Soul. Minneapolis: Augsburg Books, 2005. (Box 62)
    - African American Preaching Library, Volume 1. Editor. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 2006. (Box 62)
    - Holy Play: The Joyful Adventure of UnleashingYour Diving Purpose. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass, 2007. (Box 62)
    - Fulfilled: Living and Leading with Unusual Wisdom, Peace, and Joy. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 2013. (Box 62)
    - Refill: Meditations for Leading with Wisdom, Peace, and Joy. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 2014. (Box 62)
  - Knowles, James Davis
    - Importance of Theological Institutions: An address delivered before the trustees, students, and friends of the Newton Theological Institution, November 14, 1832. Boston: Lincoln & Edmands, 1832. (Box 63)
    - Memoir of Roger Williams, the founder of the state or Rhode Island. Boston: Lincoln, Edmands, 1834. (Box 63)
  - Lee, Simon S.
    - Jesus' Transfiguration and the Believers' Transformation: A Study of the Transfiguration and Its Development in Early Christian Writings. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2009. (Box 33)
  - Lincoln, Heman
    - "The Vatican Council and Civil Allegiance" BAPTIST QUARTERLY (April 1875): 1–16. (Box 64)
    - "New England Theology" BAPTIST QUARTERLY REVIEW 7 (1885): 267–287. (Box 64)
    - Outline Lectures on History of Doctrine. Boston: George H. Ellis, 1886. (Box 64)
    - "The Glory of the Redeemed as Related to the Work of Christ" BAPTIST QUARTERLY REVIEW 9 (January 1887): 1-23. (Box 64)
  - Linn, Edmund Holt
    - "What's wrong with preaching?" THE MINISTER'S QUARTERLY (August 1951):9–13. (Box 64)
    - PREACHING AS COUNSELING. Valley Forge: Judson Press, 1966. (Box 64)
  - Luti, J. Mary
    - Teresa of Avila's Way. The Way of Christian Mystics Series, ed. Noel Dermot O'Donoghue, ODC, no. 13. Collegeville, Minnesota: Liturgical Press, 1991. (Box 65)
    - Bibliography of J. Mary Luti., no date (Box 65)
- Individuals M-W, Series II
  - Masciarelli, Sybil Davis
    - From the Heart. [Appears to be self-published,] 1998. (Box 65)
  - Matthews, Basil
    - Christ and the World at War. ed. and intro. B.J.M. Boston: Pilgrim Press, 1917. (Box 66)
    - A Life of Jesus. New York: Richard R. Smith, Inc., 1931. (Box 66)
    - Pattern for Living. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1942. (Box 66)
    - The Church in the Changing World. Toronto: United Church of Canada, the Committee on Missionary Education, 1943. (Box 66)
  - Matthews, Shailer
    - Scientific Management in the Churches. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1912. (Box 66)
    - The Student's Gospels. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1943. (Box 66)
  - McCann, Richard Vincent
    - "The Self-Image and Delinquency: Some Implications for Religion." Federal Probation 20 (September 1956): 14–23. (Box 65)
    - "The Gift of the Self." Religious Education (May–June 1957): 163–168. (Box 65)
  - McKee, Elsie Anne
    - Diakonia in the classical reformed tradition and today. Grand Rapids: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 1989. (Box 67)
    - John Calvin on the diaconate and liturgical almsgiving. Geneva: Librare Droz S.A., 1984. (Box 67)
    - Elders and the plural ministry. Geneva: Librare Droz, 1988. (Box 67)
    - "Alexandre Vinet On Religious Liberty And Separation of Church and State." Journal Of Church And State 28 (Winter 1986): 95-106. (Box 67)
    - "Calvin's Teaching on the Elder Illuminated by Exegetical History." in Calvin Studies IV. Edited by John H. Leith and W. Stacy Johnson. 1988. 135-143 (Box 67)
    - "Calvin's Exegesis of Romans 12:8." In Calvinus Servus Christi, ed. Wilhelm H. Neuser, 237-240. Budapest: Presseabteilung des Raday-Kollegiums, 1988. (Box 67)
  - McLaughlin, Eleanor L
    - "The Heresy of the Free Spirit and Late medieval Mysticism." Medievalia et Humanistica: Studies in Medieval and Renaissance Culture 4 (1973): 37–54. (Box 85)
    - The Equality of Souls, the Inequality of Sexes: The Woman in Medieval Theology. Unpublished Manuscript. [Published in Women under Patriarchal Religion: Images of Women in the Jewish and Christian Traditions, Rosemary R. Ruether, ed., Simon & Schuster, 1973.] (Box 85)
    - "Are We Out of the Middle Ages? A Perspective on Faith and Reason." Chaplaincy Papers II (May 1, 1974). (Box 85)
    - The Christian Past: Does It Hold a Future for Women? William James Lecture in Religious Experience, May 1, 1974. [Also published in Anglican Theological Review 57 (January 1975): 36–56. And in Womanspirit rising: a feminist reader in religion, ed. Carol P. Christ and Judith Plasknow, 93–106. San Francisco: Harper and Row, 1979.] (Box 85)
    - Women in the Priesthood — and the Health of the Church. Lecture delivered at the Massachusetts Clerical Association (Episcopal Diocese of Massachusetts), May 6, 1974. (Box 85)
    - Women of Spirit: Female Leadership in the Jewish and Christian Traditions, ed. Rosemary Ruther and ELM. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1979. (Box 85)
    - "Review of The Heresy of the Free Spirit by Robert Lerner." [To be published in Speculum?], no date (Box 85)
    - The Heresy of the Free Spirit and Late Medieval Mysticism. [No publication information or date.], no date (Box 85)
  - Miller, Samuel Howard
    - "The religious interpretation of history: special reading list." BULLETIN OF THE GENERAL THEOLOGICAL LIBRARY 29 (April 1937):10–14. (Box 68)
    - THE SEASON OF THE SOUL. Cambridge, MA: [privately printed], 1943. (Box 68)
    - THE LIFE OF THE SOUL. New York: Harper, 1951. (Box 68)
    - THE LIFE OF THE CHURCH. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1953. (Box 68)
    - "Science and religion: a reading list." BULLETIN OF THE GENERAL THEOLOGICAL LIBRARY 47 (January 1955):5–8. (Box 68)
    - "Pastoral Experience and Theological Training: the Implications of Depth Psychology for Christian Theology." [No publication information, 1960.] (Box 68)
    - MAN THE BELIEVER. Nashville: Abingdon, 1968. (Box 68)
    - "When I join the church." (Whittemore Assn. tract, n.d.)., no date (Box 68)
  - Minear, Paul Sevier
    - EYES OF FAITH: A STUDY IN THE BIBLICAL POINT OF VIEW. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1946. (Box 69)
    - THE KINGDOM AND THE POWER: AN EXPOSITION OF THE NEW TESTAMENT GOSPEL. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1950. (Box 69)
    - THE CHOICE: A STORY OF CHRISTIAN FAITH. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1958. (Box 69)
    - CHRISTIAN HOPE AND THE SECOND COMING. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1954. (Box 70)
    - The Nature of the Unity We Seek: Official Report of the North American Conference on Faith and Order. St. Louis, Missouri: The Bethany Press, 1958. (Box 70)
    - Horizons of Christian Community. St. Louis, Missouri: The Bethany Press, 1959. (Box 70)
    - "Adam and the Educator." THE CHRISTIAN SCHOLAR 39/1 (March 1956): 6–18. (Box 70)
    - "Eschatology and History." Lecture prepared for cancelled Pastor's Conference in Uppsala, Sweden [unpublished]., 1949 (Box 70)
    - "The Interpreter and the Nativity Stories." Reprint from THEOLOGY TODAY 7/3 (October 1950): 358–375. (Box 70)
    - "The Wounded Beast." Published in JOURNAL OF BIBLICAL LITERATURE 72. Unpublished manuscript., 1953 (Box 70)
    - P.S.M. and Paul S. Morimoto. KIERKEGAARD AND THE BIBLE: AN INDEX. Princeton: Princeton Theological Seminary, 1953. (Box 70)
    - "Revelation and the Knowledge of the Church." The Dudleian Lecture delivered in Andover Chapel, Harvard Divinity School, April 27, 1954. (Box 70)
    - "New Starting Point: Church Renewal and Social Renewal." Interpretation 19/1 (January 1965): 3–15. (Box 70)
    - "The Constitution on Divine Revelation." Essay for Notre Dame Conference, 21 March 1966. (Box 70)
    - "God's Good News: The Biblical Basis of the Church's Missionary Obligation." [No publication information.], no date (Box 70)
    - "God's Intention Through the Church: III. The Vocie of God and the Voice of the Church." [No publication information given; note indicates possibly New England Congregational Ministers, no date.] (Box 70)
    - "Guide to the New Testament." in ANDOVER NEWTON WAYMARKS series. Newton Centre, MA: Andover Newton Theological School Public Relations Office, n.d., no date (Box 70)
  - Mobley, Greg
    - The Birth of Satan: Tracing the Devil's Biblical Roots. [joint author with Tina Wray] New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2005. (Box 71)
    - The Empty Men: The Heroic Tradition of Ancient Israel. New York: Doubleday, 2005. (Box 71)
    - "Glimpses of the Heroic Saul." In Saul in Story and Tradition. Eds. Carl S. Ehrlich and Marsha C. White. Mohr Siebeck, 2006: 80–87. (Box 71)
    - Samson and the Liminal Hero in the Ancient Near East. New York: T & T Clark, 2006. (Box 71)
    - The Return of the Chaos Monsters—and Other Backstories of the Bible. Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 2012. (Box 71)
  - Nordbeck, Elizabeth C
    - Thunder on the right: understanding conservative Christianity. New York: United Church Press, 1990. (Box 72)
    - Granite and grace: essays celebrating the two hundredth anniversary of the New Hampshire Conference United Church of Christ, ed. Charles E. Clark and Elizabeth C. Nordbeck. Concord, New Hampshire: New Hampshire Conference United Church of Christ, 2001. (Box 72)
    - Curriculum Vitae of Elizabeth C. Nordbeck., no date (Box 72)
  - O'Neal, Ellis E., Jr.
    - "A Bible, a Commentary, and a Concordance." Andover Newton Quarterly 7/2 (November 1966): 66–84. (Box 65)
    - A Bibliography of the Sources Which Contribute to an Understanding of the Life and Thought of John Bunyan. [No publication information given], 1968. (Box 65)
    - "How Are You Protecting Your Records?" The American Baptist/Massachusetts News Section (November 1974): 5. (Box 65)
    - "A Materials-Centered or a Client-Centered Library?: reactor to 'Library Collections: New Measures of Excellence,' by Thomas J. Galvin." Paper presented at the 32nd Annual Conference of the Americn Theological Library Association, Latrobe, Pa., 20 June 1978. (Box 65)
    - O'Neal, E & Yount, Diana. "Andover Newton Theological School." American Baptist Quarterly 1/1 (October 1982): 51–58. (Box 65)
  - Park, Edwards Amasa
    - "The Mode of Exhibiting Theological Truth." (October 1837): 436-478. (Box 73)
    - Bela Bates Edwards and EAP. Selections from German Literature. Andover: Gould, Newman and Saxton, 1839. (Box 73)
    - Duties of the New England Clergy: A Discourse Delivered in Boston Before the Pastoral Association of Congregational Ministers in Massachusetts. Andover: Allen, Morrill, and Wardwell, 1844. (Box 73)
    - The Preacher and Pastor. New York: M.W. Dodd, 1849. (Box 73)
    - Discourse delivered before the Convention of the Congregational Ministers of Massachusetts in Brattle Street Meeting-House, Boston, May 30, 1850. Boston: Perkins & Whipple, 1850. (Box 74)
    - The Indebtedness of the State to the Clergy: A Sermon Delivered Before His Excellency George N. Briggs … at the Annual Election, January 2, 1851. Boston: Dutton and Wentworth, 1851. (Box 74)
    - The Utility of Collegiate and Professional Schools: An Address in Behalf of the Society for the Promotion of Collegiate and Theological Education at the West. Second Edition. Andover: Warren F. Draper, 1851. (Box 74)
    - Unity Amid Diversities of Belief, Even on Imputed and Involuntary Sin. Andover, W.F. Draper, 1851. (Box 74)
    - A Discourse Delivered at the Funeral of Professor Moses Stuart. Boston: Tappen & Whittemore, 1852. (Box 74)
    - The Life and Services of Professor B.B. Edwards: A Discourse Delivered in the Chapel of Andover Theological Seminary, June 25, 1852. Andover: Press of Warren F. Draper, 1852. (Box 74)
    - Revelation of God in His Works: A Sermon Delivered at the Installation of the Rev. Jacob M. Manning…. Boston: S. K. Whipple & Company, 1857. (Box 74)
    - An Address Delivered Before the American Education Society at the Anniversary Meeting in Boston, May 30, 1865. Boston: T.R. Marvin & Son, 1865. (Box 74)
    - A Discourse Preached at the Installation of Rev. Horace H. Leavitt…. Boston: Congregational Sunday-School and Publishing Society, 1882. (Box 74)
    - Memorial Collection of Sermons, compiled by his daughter. Boston: Pilgrim Press, 1902. (Box 74)
  - Pazmiño, Robert W.
    - "Double dutch: reflections of an Hispanic North American on multicultural religious education." Unpublished manuscript. (Also published in Voces: voices from the Hispanic church, ed. Justo L. Gonzalez, 137–145. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 1992. ), 1988 (Box 75)
    - The seminary in the city: a study of New York Theological Seminary. New York: University Press of America, 1988. (Box 75)
    - Principles and practices of Christian education: an evangelical perspective. Grand Rapids, MI: Baker House Books, 1992. (Box 75)
    - By What Authority Do We Teach?: Sources for Empowering Christian Educators. Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Books, 1994. (Box 75)
    - Latin American journey: insights for Christian education in North America. Cleveland, OH: United Church Press, 1994. (Box 75)
    - "Fundamentos de currículo." Capacitando: Para Missões Transculturais 1 (1996): 44–60. (Box 75)
    - Foundational issues in Christian education: an introduction in evangelical perspective, 2nd ed. Grand Rapids: Baker Book House, 1997. (Box 75)
    - Basics of teaching for Christians. Grand Rapids: Baker Books, 1998. (Box 75)
    - Foundational issues in Christian education: an introduction in evangelical perspective. Grand Rapids: Baker Books House, 1988., 1998 (Box 75)
    - God our teacher: theological basics in Christian education. Grand Rapids: Baker Academic, 2001. (Box 75)
    - Foundational Issues in Christian Education: An Introduction in Evangelical Perspective. Third Edition. Grand Rapids: BakerAcademic, 2008. (Box 76)
    - So What Makes Our Teaching Christian?: Teaching in the Name, Spirit, and Power Of Jesus. Eugene: Wipf & Stock, 2008. (Box 76)
    - Doing Theological Research: An Introductory Guide for Survival in Theological Education. Eugene: Wipf & Stock, 2010. (Box 76)
    - A Boy Grows in Brooklyn: An Educational and Spiritual Memoir. Eugene, Oregon: Wipf & Stock, 2014. (Box 76)
    - Curriculum Vitae of Robert W. Pazmiño., no date (Box 76)
  - Pease, Theodore C.
    - The Christian Ministry and Other Writings. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin, 1894. (Box 65)
    - "Reflections on Church and Politics from Costa Rica." [Unpublished manuscript] (August 1981). (Box 65)
    - SELF AND FAMILY. Philidelphia: Westminister Press, 1984. (Box 65)
    - "The United Methodist Agenda: Teaching for Ecumenism." Quarterly Review 11/3 (1991): 71–86. (Box 65)
  - Pearson, Roy M.
    - THIS DO AND LIVE. New York: Abingdon Press, 1954. (Box 77)
    - THE HARD COMMANDS OF JESUS. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 1957. (Box 77)
    - SEEKING AND FINDING GOD. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 1958. (Box 77)
    - THE MINISTRY OF PREACHING. New York: Harper, 1959. (Box 77)
    - HEAR OUR PRAYER: PRAYERS FOR PUBLIC WORSHIP. New York: McGraw Hill, 1961. (Box 77)
    - THE PREACHER: HIS PURPOSE AND PRACTICE. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1962. (Box 77)
    - THE BELIEVER'S UNBELIEF: A LAYMAN'S GUIDE THROUGH CHRISTIAN DOUBT. New York: T. Nelson, 1963. (Box 77)
    - HAPPY ARE THE HUNGRY. Sermon delivered in the First Congregational Church, Amherst, Massachusetts, on February 23, 1941. (printed as a gift by a loyal member of the church) (Box 78)
    - THE CHURCHMAN SERMON OF THE WEEK. text of sermon broadcast on WOR radio at 10:30 a.m., February 23, 1947 by announcer Fredric March, with introduction by Dr. Guy Emery Shipler. (Box 78)
    - THE CHURCHMAN SERMON OF THE WEEK. text of sermon broadcast on WOR radio at 9:15 a.m., April 18, 1948 by announcer Robert St. John, with introduction by Dr. Guy Emery Shipler. (Box 78)
    - WHEN JESUS CAME TO HANCOCK CHURCH. Sermon on Matthew 16:24–26, John 21:15–17 delivered 10 February 1952. (unpublished typewritten manuscript) (Box 78)
    - "Why are we Protestants?" THE PULPIT DIGEST 35 (October 1954): 49–56. (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that all of the first twelve apostles were men and that much of the work of the church which is most needed today must still be done by men." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, October 16, 1955.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that the sacrament of the Lord's supper is more important than many people think." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, May 1, 1955.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that when Jesus went up to Jerusalem, he went triumphantly. And so can we!" (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, April 3, 1955.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that all of us face temptations and that one of the secrets of living triumphantly is learning how to deal with temptations." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, July 29, 1956.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that God has a will for every one of us and that we find life's glory when we find God's will. (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, July 1, 1956.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that if there is one sense in which Christianity should NOT have anything to do with politics, there is another sense in which it SHOULD." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, October 21, 1956.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that many people don't go to church because the church service bores them and that some people who go, come wishing they hadn't." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, October 21, 1956.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that the holiday called Thanksgiving has deeper meaning than many people either know or desire." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, November 18, 1956.) (Box 78)
    - DRINKING. Boston: Whittimore Assoc., 1956. (Box 78)
    - "Chosen for obedience." PULPIT PREACHING (June 1957): 3–6. (Box 78)
    - "On keeping ministers alive." CHRISTIAN ADVOCATE (April 1957): 14–16. (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that Christian love and marriage are among our newest institutions. (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, May, 5, 1957.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that getting into step with men sometimes means getting out of step with God." (Unpublished radio address Massachusetts Council of Churches, January 13, 1957.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that more people own a Bible than read it and that more people read it than understand it." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, March 10, 1957.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that most of us can recognize the weaknesses of everyone except ourselves." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, February 10, 1957.) (Box 78)
    - "This I know—that the church is the body of Christ." (Unpublished radio address, Massachusetts Council of Churches, June 2, 1957.) (Box 78)
    - "Meditation for ministers." MINISTER'S QUARTERLY 14 (June 1958): 9–11. (Box 78)
    - "The marks of a great church." THE ALUMNI BULLETIN OF BANGOR THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY 33 (July 1958): 1–5. (Box 78)
    - "Free men." FOUNDATIONS 2 (October 1959): 349–355. (Box 78)
    - "No meetings in heaven." LUTHERAN HERALD 43 (July 28, 1959): 2–4. (Box 78)
    - The people of God. Sermon on I Peter 2:1–10 preached at the rededication of the First Congregational Church of Falmouth, January 22, 1961. (unpublished typewritten manuscript) (Box 78)
    - "Loose tackle." MINISTER'S QUARTERLY 18 (Summer 1962): 28–29. (Box 78)
    - "The give and take between science and religion." JOURNAL OF AMERICAN SCIENTIFIC AFFILIATION (March 1963): 4–6. (Box 78)